Abimbola Balogun

With 5+ years of experience in React, React Native, and Javascript. Specialized in building and maintaining web and mobile applications for thousands of users, focusing on application security, responsiveness, and scalability. A team player with strong communication skills, committed to creating effective solutions that align with business needs.

Relevant Experience

Fullstack Engineer at OnePort365 Feb 2022 — Present

- Co-Led a cross-functional team to develop West Africa's first digital freight forwarding management application, serving 10,000+ clients.
- Developed a comprehensive booking system for freight forwarding using Typescript for the front end development, allowing customers to select shipment types (Import/ Export) and desired services including Ocean Freight, Haulage, Air Freight, Custom Brokerage and Warehousing
- Built, styled, and shipped high quality websites, design systems, mobile apps, and crossplatform digital experiences for a diverse array of clients using technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, CSS, WordPress, Contentful, and more.
- Championed the setup and configuration of a React based application, accurately translating complex designs into functional interfaces, architecting optimized database schemas, and crafting robust API endpoints.
- Implemented an integrated invoicing feature and seamlessly integrated with QuickBooks, enhancing financial management capabilities and streamlining finance operations for the team.
- Provided leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, building tools to improve developer experience, and mentorship.
- Managed the deployment and maintenance of MongoDB clusters, ensuring high availability of the OnePort 365 web application which resulted in a 30% reduction in downtime.

Frontend Engineer at Tunga April 2023 — June 2024

- Utilized React Native to design and implement responsive, high-performance user interfaces for a mobile application called Fanect, ensuring a seamless user experience across both iOS and Android platforms.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to translate wireframes and mockups into interactive and visually appealing mobile app screens, focusing on user engagement and accessibility
- Employed ReactJS to build and enhance the admin dashboard, creating intuitive and
 efficient management tools for administrators to monitor and manage user activities,
 content, and analytics.
- Managed deployment processes using Cloudways and AWS, ensuring reliable and scalable hosting solutions for both the mobile application. This included setting up continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, monitoring server performance, and optimizing resource usage to ensure high availability and low latency.
- Utilized Firebase to ensure secure and scalable delivery of the admin dashboard application updates and real-time database management for user-generated content

Junior Frontend Engineer at Lenilabs Jan 2021 — Feb 2022 Frontend Intern Dec 2019 — Jan 2021

ontona intern dec 2015 — San 2021

- Implemented a highly developed GraphQL APIs for a high-traffic e-commerce web
 applications (https://www.artgidi.com/), improving data retrieval efficiency by 30% as
 well as building GraphQL queries and mutations to streamline data access, resulting in
 a 25% reduction in backend response times.
- Deployed and developed scalable GraphQL schemas for a SaaS application (https://www.mayfairdesignstudio.ng/), enhancing client-side data fetching and reducing payload sizes by 20%
- Created intuitive admin dashboards for e-commerce and e-Library applications, improving user management and data analysis, resulting in a 30% boost in productivity and data-driven decision-making.
- Crafted professional and responsive websites for corporate firms, showcasing their brand identity and driving online presence, resulting in a 40% increase in website traffic and user engagement.
- Engineered a web application for dispatch operations, integrating Google Maps for precise geolocation services, optimizing delivery efficiency by 25% and reducing transportation costs by 15%.
- Solicited and incorporated feedback from colleagues to streamline the software development life cycle, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time and improved team efficiency.

+1 (613)-978-4243 427 Cope Drive, Ottawa Ontario github.com/olorunyomi97 Abimbola's LinkedIn

Skills

Programming Languages

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Sass, PHP, GraphQL

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Redux, React Native, VueJs, Vuex, Next.Js, Gatsby, Node.Js, ExpressJs, AngularJS, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components, Laravel, Code Igniter Jest, Bootstrap

Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, Firebase, Storybook, Webpack, Figma, MongoDB, phpMyAdmin, HTTP, RestfulAPIs, Context API, ReactQuery, JQuery, Babel, Storybook, Ajax, Postgres

Miscellaneous

Agile and Scrum Fundamentals, Market Research, SSL/OAuth, MacOS, Caching, DOM, UI/UX Design, Restful, NPM, Linux

Selected Projects

OnePort365

A comprehensive booking system for global freight forwarding, primarily using TypeScript, React, Tailwind CSS, and Node.js.

Mayfair Studio Designs

To think forward, do more collaborative designs for a better future.

Abimbola's Website

Personal website built with Gatsby and deployed on netlify.

Education

University Of Lagos.

Bachelor Of Science in Process Engineering.

Lighthouse Labs

Diploma in Web Development.

Interests

Web Accessibility, Anime, Gaming